<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>CloudCat Digital</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on CloudCat Digital</description>
    <image>
      <title>CloudCat Digital</title>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/images/logo_small.jpg</url>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/images/logo_small.jpg</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>A Beginner&#39;s Guide to DNS</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/domain_name_servers_guide/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/domain_name_servers_guide/</guid>
      <description>A Beginner&amp;rsquo;s Guide to DNS - From Domain Purchase to Establishing Your Online Presence The Common Query: What Happens After Buying a Domain? As an IT professional with a sysadmin background and cloud infrastructure focus, I often get DNS-related questions from programmers and colleagues who are just starting out with their own websites. One common confusion that arises post-purchase is about the role and setup of DNS hosting. This post aims to clarify these concepts, using my own experience with setting up https://cloudcat.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Integrating Helm Hooks with HashiCorp Vault for Cloud Migrations</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/helm_hooks_manage_secrets/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/helm_hooks_manage_secrets/</guid>
      <description>Managing Secrets in Kubernetes with Helm and HashiCorp Vault In the dynamic landscape of cloud migrations, securely and efficiently managing application configurations, particularly secrets, is a critical task. This article explores a practical scenario where an organization is migrating its applications from on-premises infrastructure to Amazon EKS, using HashiCorp Vault&amp;rsquo;s CSI driver to handle secrets. Here, we&amp;rsquo;ll dive into the challenges and solutions of using environment variables to access these secrets—a common yet sensitive practice—and provide a step-by-step guide to implementing robust solutions using Helm hooks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Embracing Open Container Initiative for Helm Charts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/oci_charts/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/oci_charts/</guid>
      <description>A New Perspective on Helm Charts Whale hello there (docker pun) DevOps enthusiasts! As someone who&amp;rsquo;s been navigating the waters of AWS and Helm for years, I&amp;rsquo;ve largely relied on the tried-and-tested methods like ChartMuseum and S3 backends for managing Helm charts. Occasionally, I&amp;rsquo;ve also pulled charts directly from version control when the stakes weren&amp;rsquo;t too high on audit trails, because it&amp;rsquo;s straightforward and gets the job done when conditions allow.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Microservices VS Serverless</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/microservices_vs_serverless/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/microservices_vs_serverless/</guid>
      <description>In the dynamic world of software architecture, the debate between microservices and serverless functions (like AWS Lambda) is similar to the classic face-off between Ryu and Ken in the Street Fighter world. Both have their strengths, their unique moves, and their situational advantages. As developers, we&amp;rsquo;re often in the position to make a choice between the two, so let&amp;rsquo;s break down the details in a clear, concise, and human manner.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Making Caching Work for You in CI</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/github_self_hosted_caching/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/github_self_hosted_caching/</guid>
      <description>A Practical Guide for GitHub Self-Hosted Runners Hey everyone, today let&amp;rsquo;s talk about something that can make a real difference in your CI pipelines: effective caching. If you&amp;rsquo;ve been following along, you know we&amp;rsquo;ve explored using Docker registry mirror before. In our last post, we talked about the context and challenge of CI cache in a dynamic and fully scalable environment. Since our setup is like a revolving door with nodes coming and going based on demand, holding onto a Docker cache is like trying to catch smoke with your bare hands.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>GitHub Actions, self-hosted runners with Scale-Sets tips and tricks</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/github_self_hosted_dind/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/github_self_hosted_dind/</guid>
      <description>As someone who&amp;rsquo;s spent a fair bit of time tinkering with CI/CD pipelines and automating infrastructure, I&amp;rsquo;ve really started to see the value in GitHub Actions, particularly after moving away from Jenkins. My journey took an exciting turn when I began experimenting with self-hosted GitHub Actions runners on Kubernetes, using the summerwinds actions runner controller. Things got even more interesting when I shifted to scale-sets, thanks to GitHub embracing the ARC project.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DevOps and DevOps Accessories</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/devops_and_accessories/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/devops_and_accessories/</guid>
      <description>Remember Hank Hill from &amp;ldquo;King of the Hill&amp;rdquo;? He was all about propane and propane accessories. That&amp;rsquo;s kind of like me but with DevOps instead. And like Hank&amp;rsquo;s, my passion with computers started in my childhood, in the &amp;rsquo;90s, a time when they were not just scarce but symbolized a window to a whole new world for me. The first time I encountered a Commodore-like PC sparked a whole new level of excitement and my fascination only grew as I discovered the magic of graphics and network capabilities.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>We are a DevOps boutique firm based in Bucharest, with over 10 years of experience in cloud computing, SRE, and platform engineering.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/contact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
